JENNIFER **FUHRER**

Passionate senior software engineer with a Top Secret SCI clearance seeks a full-time position with a diverse and dynamic enterprise.

Positive team player offers practical experience and a personal commitment to excellence through collaboration and cooperation.



EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer | Two Six Technologies

APRIL 2022 - PRESENT | ARLINGTON, VA

- Researches and writes proposals for government entities, including a cellular communications testing software proposal for a DARPA SBIR-XL program, working directly with a DARPA Program Manager.
- Leads a development team to prototype a collection of ML tools to analyze the social data from open-source repositories. Integrated models developed by ML engineers into a Python web-interface.
- Designed and implemented Python tools to capture metrics about the cellular and data connection of an embedded device. Integrated scripts with existing infrastructure and created a web-interface for visualizing the captured metrics.
- Developed and tested software to interface with a cellular module for an embedded Linux device.
- Documented and compiled team's monthly progress into customer facing technical reports.
- Developed automated CI/CD pipeline for unit tests during the development cycle of projects.

Software Engineer II | Grier Forensics

JUNE 2020 - MARCH 2022 | OWINGS MILLS, MD

- Led efforts to research and write project proposals for Air Force and DARPA SBIR topics.
- Designed and developed custom communication protocols at the IP layer in C++ to efficiently share and verify the credentials of airborne systems participating in a secure network.
- Created a Command Line Interface and the framework to support its communication with an Airborne Cyber Defense application in Python.

Intelligent Physical Systems (ECE 3400) Teaching Assistant | Cornell University AUGUST 2018 – DECEMBER 2018 | ITHACA, NY

• Administered lab sections and held open office hours for students creating a maze mapping robot. Assisted students building analog circuits and developing on embedded devices.



EDUCATION

Electrical and Computer Engineering B.S. | Cornell University

AUGUST 2015 – MAY 2019 | ECE WOMAN OF THE MONTH (NOVEMBER 2018)
Organizations: Autonomous Underwater Vehicle Project Team (CUAUV), Guild of Visual Arts (GVA)
Projects:

• **Groovy Times** | *Published in Circuit Cellar (April 2020, Issue 357)* - Wireless hand-gesture rhythm game using PIC32s, Arduinos, RF radios, and an accelerometer



SKILLS

- Languages (proficient): Python, C, C++
- Languages (familiar): Bash/Shell, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS
- Software/Platforms: Linux, Git, Docker, Grafana, Dash (Plotly), AWS, GitHub, GitLab, Atlassian
- Embedded Development: 4G Cellular Modems (Quectel), PIC32, FRDM-K64F, Arduino
- Technical Writing: Proposals, User/Development Guides, and Presentations for non-technical audiences